

Michael Soquat

Fullstack Developer

About Me

Michael Soquat
Am Vogelbaum 10
92289 Ursensollen
0049/17645603198
michael.soquat@gmx.de

Portfolio: www.michael-soquat.de

I am a Web Developer with experience in building web apps with JavaScript & Angular. You can find my projects that include responsive websites and business apps in my public porftolio. My journey began with coding small websites at home before deciding to get professional training and build projects. I am looking forward to building on my experience and starting my career in IT in a junior developer position. I am a person who is always focused and puts 100% energy into the job.

Main Stack:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript, Angular
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Python
- Django
- UI-Path(RPA)

Side Stack:

- Git, APIs (REST), Google Firebase, Docker, MySQL
- Scrum

Skills

- Building Applications with JavaScript & Angular: I built landing-pages and several web apps as well as OOP-based Jump-and-Run-Games with the respective technologies.
- Working in a Software-Team: During learning coding, I did several group projects where I learnt how to develop a software project in a team.
- **High sense of responsibility:** I am used to taking responsibility and working diligently as I always did in my job as a police officer.
- High degree of self discipline: During my life I had to work hard to achieve what I set out to do. I never gave up before getting the perfect result.

Professional Experience

Silbury/ Software-Developer

August 2022 - now - Software Developer/Fürth

- Implemented a perfect working background robot for process automation (RPA)
- Hosted an Angular web application with docker container on my own
- Built several web apps with Angular/React

Police / Police tactics trainer

January 2016 - Juli 2022 - Police Station / Amberg

- Professional instructor of self defense, shooting, tactics training.
- Responsibility for over 600 police officers acting according to rules in operations.
- Daily experience in giving lectures to communicate the theoretical tactical knowledge to up to 24 police officers/ other trainers.
- Fundamental requirements as a trainer are: Always stay focused and work exactly.

Police / Police officer

September 2011 - December 2015 Police Station / Amberg

In my career as a police officer i got these specific skills:

- Fingertip feeling about how to communicate right.
- Experience working in a team.
- A lot of responsibility for implementing laws.
- Teaching police rookies is a very hard job. In many operations I was on my own. Nevertheless I always kept a cool head in stressful situations
- Because of the diversity of operations at different times
 I learned to always be flexible.

Education

Developer academy / Front-End Developer education JavaScript & Angular Development Training

December 2021 - August 2022, Munich

Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular

Portfolio: www.michael-soquat.de

Extensive Coding School, Learning Front-End Development, Coding, Agile Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

Police task force

April 2011 - August 2011, Dachau

Special training in a task force named "USK". I got the ability to lead groups.

Police academy

September 2008 - March 2011, Sulzbach-Rosenberg

Training as a police officer.

_

College

September 2006 - August 2008, FOS Amberg

I did my vocational diploma.

Languages

German: native

English: fluent